Contact details:

email: shobhitsingh29@gmail.com

Mobile: 8909159288

Summary:

Shobhit Singh is Software Developer in PAYTM Noida office, before PAYTM he has worked for Saxo bank and Sapient. HTML, CSS, SASS, javascript(advanced), reactjs(advanced), redux, saga, jquery, angularjs(1.5x)(advanced), Handlebars-Templating, GIT, Webpack, sockets, SVN and Bootstrap knowledge. Shobhit is one of the performers of sapient's 2015 Xt batch and has been highly recognized and appreciated by mentors, managers and peers for the hard work, coding as well as level of thinking.

Work Experience:

PAYTM, April 2018 till present

Software developer: Paytm payments -UMP(unified merchant portal)

- Revamping and rewriting front-end using preact js,redux, saga,webpack.
- Architecture and Code-Base setup .

Software developer: Paytm payments Bank -BOP(Back Office Panel)

• Revamping, implementing functionalities and rewriting front-end using react.js,redux, saga,webpack...

SAXO BANK, July 2017 till March 2018

Senior Associate Developer: Open API samples

The objective was to develop modules with different major functionalities which resembles the main Saxo Trader Application features, using the same api's of main trading platform, which can be used by other white label clients so as to give better understanding of code and features.

- Implemented front-end using react js,redux, webpack,node js
- Re-implemented another minor sample using javascript, webpack.

Senior Associate Developer: Chat-Bot for query resolution

The objective was to develop a chatbot which customers or clients will be able to use to connect with saxo team in order to resolve queries .

• Implemented front end as well as backend using react js,redux,webpack,sockets,node js

Sapient Corporation, October 2015 till June 2017

Interactive Developer- Asset Tracker (Internal project IAP phase-1 and IAP phase-2) Duration: october 2015 to january 2016 The objective of this project was to develop AssetTracker.com website for managing assets like mobile, tablets, laptops, etc for sapient studio team.

- Was highly recognized and appreciated by mentors ,managers and peers as best performer of both the IAP-phases.
- · Created different components and as well as project architecture for front-end and backend.
- · Lead the whole team successfully and helped his peers while displaying core values of sapient

Interactive Developer- Hire Buddy (Shadow Project) Duration: february 2016 till april 2016 The objective of this project is to build an application for the Sapient Hiring Team, to streamline the process of hiring.

- \bullet Implemented front-end using angular js(1.5x)
- Project setup and architecture setup

Associate L1 - vaseline track (project unilever) in noida branch Duration: may 2016 to june 2016

The objective of this project was to develop vasiline.us website.

• Implemented front-end using css,html and javascript

Associate L1 - tresemme track (project unilever) in gurgaon branch Duration: august 2016 to october 2016 The objective of this project was to develop tresemme website.

- Implemented front-end using scss,handlebars,html and javascript
- created components and responsive pages.

Associate L1 - Internal assignment (project: Boston Consulting Group) in gurgaon branch Duration: november 2016 to december 2016 The objective of this project was to develop Project Tree like Structure with nodes having functionality of drag,move,edit,delete and expand-collapse.

- Implemented front-end using Backbone js,scss,html and jquery
- Project setup and architecture setup

Associate L1 – European Tour project in gurgaon branch Duration : January 2017 to March 2017 The objective of this project was to develop European tour website.

- Implemented front-end using scss,handlebars,html and javascript
- Created components and responsive pages.
- Carried out integration support along with backend team for various functionalities.

Education:

HARCOURT BUTLER TECHNOLOGICAL INSTITUTE -KANPUR

B.TECH - COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, Percentage - 72.28 %

PINEWOOD PUBLIC SCHOOL - SAHARANPUR

CBSE. Percentage - 86.2 %

SAHARANPUR PUBLIC SCHOOL - SAHARANPUR.

ICSE. Percentage - 86.2 %

Skills:

Languages :HTML,CSS,SASS,javascript(Es6,Es5),handlebars Templating(HBSS)

Library :JQuery,React js, redux,saga Framework :Bootstrap, Angularjs(1.5x)

Database : SQL

Other :Webpack,Socket,STASH,GIT,jira,Webstorm,,Sublime,Visual Studio Code,Atom.